# Mohammad Abdul Ahad Chowdhury

+61482605155 • ahad@maacpiash.com • www.maacpiash.com • www.linkedin.com/in/maacpiash • github.com/maacpiash

### PROFILE SUMMARY

Bangladeshi graduate student of data science, with one year of professional experience in full-stack web development. Proficient in developing cloud-native web applications (ASP.NET Core, MERN-stack) and machine learning solutions. Currently looking for a part-time, contract, or casual employment in the IT industry.

#### **EDUCATION**

• Macquarie University

Master of Data Science

Coursework: Data Science, Big Data, Machine Learning [Repositories on GitHub]

Sydney, NSW, Australia February 2020 – May 2022

January 2014 - August 2018

Dhaka, Bangladesh

• North South University

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering

Capstone project: Fruit Image Classification Using Convolutional Neural Networks

Coursework: Artificial Intelligence, Theory of Fuzzy Systems, Software Engineering, Microprocessor Interfacing &

Embedded System, Computer Graphics [Repositories on GitHub]

## Work Experience

# • Dynamic Solution Innovators Ltd.

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Junior Software Engineer

February 2019 - January 2020

Full-time employment working on Node.js-based full-stack web applications: following agile methodology (scrum).

**Projects**: The OpenCRVS project [commits on GitHub]; the enterprise solution of Olwel, a healthcare startup.

Responsibilities: Added components and bug-fixes to client-side software (React.js, Electron.js); added features, optimizations, and bug-fixes to server-side software (Hapi.js); optimized database queries and wrote database migration scripts (RethinkDB); wrote unit tests (Jest).

## • North South University

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Research Assistant

November 2016 - April 2018

Part-time employment under the Department of Environmental Science and Management. (<u>relevant news article</u>)

**Project**: NODES, an airline management system that uses linear optimization to maximize utilization of resources.

Responsibility: Developed the front-end software (.NET Framework, Windows Forms) of NODES.

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming languages: C#, JavaScript (ES6), TypeScript, Python, C, Java, C++, R
- Web development: ASP.NET Core, Entity Framework Core, Razor, Blazor, SignalR, Node.js, Express.js, Hapi.js, Nest.js, React.js, Next.js, Gatsby.js, Vue.js, Angular (2+), Webpack, PWA, ReST, GraphQL, Socket.IO, Microservices architecture
- Machine learning & data science: Jupyter Notebook, NumPy, Pandas, NLTK, Scikit-Learn, ML.NET
- Desktop app development: Windows Forms, WPF, UWP, Electron.js, JavaFX
- Database systems: MongoDB, MySQL, Microsoft SQL Server, PostgreSQL, SQLite, RethinkDB
- DevOps: Docker, Heroku, Netlify, Azure App Service, SSH, VPS services (e.g. Linode), MongoDB Atlas, basic CI/CD

#### Personal Projects

- KonSchool: Fuzzy-AHP-based recommendation system for secondary schools in Bangladesh. ASP.NET Core, Docker, MongoDB [GitHub Azure Heroku Docker]
- Connery: Fruit-image-classifier using convolutional neural networks. ML.NET, ASP.NET Core [GitHub] API Swagger]
- AddLicenseHeader: A CLI tool that adds a license header on top of source files. .NET Core [GitHub] NuGet package]
- Vardict: A basic Node.js package for parsing labeled CLI arguments. Node.js, TypeScript [GitHub] NPM package
- Winston: Implementation of neural networks, from scratch. WIP. C, Cmake [GitHub]

## **PUBLICATION**

- Selection of Most Suitable Secondary School Alternative by Multi-Criteria Fuzzy Analytic Hierarchy Process. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-98678-4\_29 [Slide presentation: youtu.be/lztxu5F9Sxg]
- Fruit Image Classification Using Convolutional Neural Networks. https://doi.org/10.4018/ijsi.2019100103
- Fusion of BWM and AHP MCDM Methods to Choose the Most Suitable Secondary School for an Individual in the Context of Bangladesh. https://doi.org/10.1142/s2196888819500167

Last updated on March 6, 2021. The latest version of this document can be found at pia.sh/resume